Guide to the Nicholas Scoppetta Papers 1974-2015 MS 3017
New-York Historical Society
- Series IV. Memorabilia, 1970s-circa 2009 (bulk, 2002-2009); 1 Linear feet
  - Subseries IV.A. Memorabilia: Photographs and awards, 1970s-2001
    - [Poster] The Big Apple / You have to be a little crazy to live in New York, but you'd be nuts to live anywhere else. April '76., 1976 April (Oversize Large [NS12])
      Inscribed "To my good friend Nick Scoppetta / With great affection and warm regards / Abe Beame."
  - Subseries IV.B. Memorabilia: Political and lapel pins, commemorative medals, etc., 1978-2009
    Box 9, Folder 4 contains an FDNY 9-11 arm patch and six political pins: "NICK SCOPPETTA FOR ATTORNEY GENERAL" (circa 1978); "Rudy"; "NOVEMBER 8 / MIKE / BLOOMBERG / '05"; "VINCIAMO CON / BLOOMBERG / '05"; "We Want / F.D.R. / Again"; "ACS / Latino Empowerment for the Millennium / Empoderamiento Latino Para el Milenio / Latino Heritage Month 99"
    The small leather case in Box 9 holds seven commemorative medals and about forty lapel pins / awareness ribbons, mostly from Scoppetta's time as FDNY Commissioner. With a bracelet inscribed "SERGIO VILLANUEVA / 9-11-01 FDNY LADDER 132."
    The political pins are pinned to sheets of archival paper in Box 9, Folder 4. The lapel pins and commemorative medals, some of which are still sealed in the plastic pouches in which they came, are unsorted.
    - [Political pins], 1978-2005 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 4)
    - [Lapel pins and commemorative medals], circa 2002-2009 (Offsite-box 9 [in small leather case])